Finding Aid for David W. Osler papers, 1956-2014
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Architectural Drawings
  - Sandall, Dr. Gary, Residence (1978)
    - Perspective Drawings by David W. Osler, 7/1978; 2 drawings pencil-on-vellum originals (Map-case 3, Folder 8)
  - St. Clare of Assisi Episcopal Church, Packard Street, Ann Arbor, Michigan (1967-1969)
    - Preliminary Drawings by David W. Osler, undated; 1 drawings perspective; 3 drawings architectural drawings; pencil-on-vellum originals (Map-case 5, Folder 10)
    - Construction Drawings by David W. Osler, Architect, and Migdal, Layne & Sachs, Inc. Engineers, 4/10/1967-3/19/1969; 17 drawings architectural, mechanical and electrical drawings; pencil-on-vellum originals (Map-case 5, Folder 10)
  - St. James Episcopal Church, West Maple Road, Birmingham, Michigan (1994)
    - Schematic Design and Design Development Drawings by David W. Osler Associates, Inc., Architects, 2/28/1994-4/25/1994; 38 drawings perspectives, sketches and architectural drawings; pencil and ink originals on tracing paper, vellum and mylar and CAD drawings on mylar (Map-case 5, Folder 11)
  - Sallade, George Wahr, Apartment Project, Division and Ann Streets, Ann Arbor, Michigan (1973)
    - Design Development Drawings by David W. Osler, Architect, and Washtenaw Engineering Co., Inc. (, 1/24/1973-01/30/1973; 18 drawings perspectives, surveys and architectural drawings; pencil and ink originals on vellum and on blue-line and sepia prints (Map-case 5, Folder 12)
  - Schmeichel Residence, Daleview Drive, Scio Township, Ann Arbor, Michigan (1980)
    - Construction Drawings by Osler Milling Architects, Inc., 4/11/1980-8/4/1980; 12 drawings architectural and electrical drawings; pencil-on-vellum originals (Map-case 5, Folder 10)
  - Senior Center (proposed), Packard Street, Ann Arbor, Michigan
    - Perspective Drawing by David W. Osler, undated; 1 drawings pencil-on-vellum original (Map-case 3, Folder 8)
  - Sigma Phi House (Alpha of Michigan of Sigma Phi Corp.), University of Michigan, Lincoln Avenue, Ann Arbor, Michigan (1963)
    - Construction Drawings by David W. Osler, Architect, and Cummins and Barnard, Engineers, 10/15/1963; 22 drawings architectural, structural and mechanical, electrical;plumbing drawings; pencil drawings on vellum and sepia prints (Map-case 5, Folder 13)
  - Stipe, Mr. & Mrs. George, Residence, Highland Terrace Subdivision, Ann Arbor, Michigan (1966)
    - Construction Drawings by David W. Osler, Architect, 8/22/1966; 16 drawings architectural, mechanical and electrical drawings; pencil-on-vellum originals (Map-case 5, Folder 12)
  - Stockstiel, Mr. & Mrs. C., Residence, Sylvania Township, Ohio (1965-1966)
    - Construction Drawings by David W. Osler, Architect, 9/17/1965-5/8/1966; 16 drawings architectural, mechanical and electrical drawings; pencil-on-vellum originals (Map-case 5, Folder 13)
  - Talahai Retreat Center, United Church of Christ, Pinkney, Michigan (1984)
    - Preliminary Drawings, one dated, 1/10/1984; 1 drawings perspective; 1 blueprints; pencil-on-vellum originals (Map-case 3, Folder 8)
  - University of Michigan Engineering Building Arch, Ann Arbor, Michigan (undated)
    - Original painting by David W. Osler, 1 paintings; 1 prints (Map-case 1, Folder 14)
      (print from the Franklin DeKleine Company Collection)
  - University of Michigan Women's Field Hockey Training and Locker Facility, Ann Arbor, Michigan (1995)
    - Preliminary Drawing by David W. Osler Associates, Architects, Inc., 10/19/1995; 1 drawings colored pencil drawing on electrostatic print (Map-case 6, Folder 1)
  - Vietnam War Veterans Memorial Competition, Washington, D.C. (1980-1981)
    - Presentation Board I, undated; 3 drawings site plans, elevations (orthographic projections) and sections (orthographic projections); electrostatic copies on tempered masonite (Map-case 6, Folder 6)
    - Presentation Board II, undated; 4 drawings perspective, elevation and section drawings; electrostatic copies on tempered masonite (Map-case 6, Folder 7)
    - Design Competition Program and Winners' Exhibition Brochure, 1980-1981 (Map-case 2, Folder 13)
    - Competition Drawings
      - Conceptual Design Sketches, undated; pencil sketches on yellow notebook paper (Map-case 2, Folder 13)
      - Conceptual Sketches on Design Competition Site Plans, 12/31/1980; original sketches on one print (Map-case 2, Folder 13)
      - Site Plans and Perspective Drawings, including Landscape Sketches and Notes by Charles W. Cares, Landscape Architect, undated; 7 drawings pencil drawings; on tracing paper and vellum (Map-case 2, Folder 13)
      - Site Plans and Perspective Drawings, undated; pencil drawings on four sheets of artist's paper (Map-case 2, Folder 13)
      - Presentation Board Mock-up (Map-case 2, Folder 13)
  - Voorhees, Mr. & Mrs. William S., Residence, Davidson County, Tennessee (1963)
    - Construction Drawings by David W. Osler, Architect, 7/18/1963; 15 drawings architectural, mechanical and electrical drawings; pencil-on-vellum originals (Map-case 6, Folder 2)
  - Washtenaw Community College Child Care and Family Education Center, Ann Arbor, Michigan
    - Perspective Drawing by David W. Osler, undated; 1 drawings pencil-on-vellum original (Map-case 6, Folder 1)
  - Washtenaw County 14th District Court, Michigan Avenue, Ypsilanti, Michigan (1977-1978)
    - Preliminary Drawings by David W. Osler, Architect, David W. Osler & Partners, Inc., Midwest Consulting, Inc., and Atwell-Hicks, Inc., 8/30/1977-10/11/1978; 1 drawings perspective; 22 drawings surveys and architectural drawings; pencil-on-vellum originals and blue-line prints (Map-case 6, Folder 2)
  - Washtenaw County League for Planned Parenthood Clinic, Washtenaw County, Michigan
    - Perspective Drawing by David W. Osler, undated; 1 drawings pencil-on-vellum original (Map-case 6, Folder 1)
  - Washtenaw County Library, Washtenaw County Farm. Washtenaw Avenue and Platt Road, Ann Arbor, Michigan (1966)
    - Construction Drawings by David W. Osler, Architect 4/22/1966 revised 11/12/1966, 24 drawings architectural, structural and mechanical, electrical;plumbing drawings; pencil-on-vellum originals (Map-case 6, Folder 3)
  - White Motor Corporation Faade Remodeling, Detroit, Michigan
    - Perspective Drawing by Osler Milling Architects, Inc., undated; 1 drawings pencil-on-vellum original (Map-case 6, Folder 1)
  - Williams Research, Inc., Office Building, Maple Road, Walled Lake, Michigan (1971-1973)
    - Construction Drawings by David W. Osler, Architect, and Robert M. Darvas, Structural Engineer to /16/1973, 2/12/1971; 1 drawings perspective; 35 drawings architectural, structural and mechanical;electrical drawings; pencil-on-vellum originals (Map-case 6, Folder 4)
  - Woodruff, James F. & Ann T., Commercial Development, Athens, Georgia
    - Preliminary Drawings by David W. Osler, undated; 1 drawings perspective drawing; 1 site plans; pencil-on-vellum originals (Map-case 6, Folder 1)